<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Devices - Category - Pdleon Blog</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/categories/devices/</link>
        <description>Devices - Category - Pdleon Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/categories/devices/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>AudioCodes ATA Teams SIP Gateway Integration</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/2024-02-19-audiocodes-ata-teams-sip-gateway-integration/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>David Ponce de Leon</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/2024-02-19-audiocodes-ata-teams-sip-gateway-integration/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Overview In an attempt to review the integration of an ATA to the Teams SIP Gateway, purchased an AudioCodes MP112 as the simplest and cheapest option.
AudioCodes recently released an onbarding guide as a walkthrough but typically there are always hidden assumptions that might stomp the process.
Audiocodes ATA MP1xx Teams SIP Gateway Integration
Requirements MP1xx
Crossover cable
Analog endpoint
Device Firmware:
Microsoft supported firmware - 6.60A.367.[001-005] (at the time of writing) Download firmware directly from AC or download from here (at the time of writing) : MP-11x FXS/FXO 6.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Teams SIP Gateway - Enable and Provision Polycom VVX 500</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/2021-12-07-sip-gateway/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>David Ponce de Leon</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/2021-12-07-sip-gateway/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction When this new feature was released, it was time to dust my old Polycom VVX 500 phone and provision it for Teams basic call functionality.
The official Microsoft documentation for all the pre-requisites and supported devices can be found here:
https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoftteams/sip-gateway-plan
https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoftteams/sip-gateway-configure
Procedure Enable your custom or global policy to enable SIP devices can be used for calls I went deep dive immediately and ignored a very important step which caused me some wasted time and some troubleshooting efforts.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Poly Lens - Getting Started</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/2021-08-19-poly-lens/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>David Ponce de Leon</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/2021-08-19-poly-lens/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction Managing phones through Teams Admin Center has been challenging at times especially when staying up to date with firmware and application updates. Part of the challenge is that the phones at time do not register correctly, do not reflect immediate changes, do not appear in the dashboard at times, and fail to update when pushing the update. These challenges can be prevented or minimized by having correct compliance policies, accurate configuration and solid network connectivity.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Teams Device Monitoring and Alerting Offline Status</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/2021-06-23-teams-device-monitoring-and-alerting/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>David Ponce de Leon</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/2021-06-23-teams-device-monitoring-and-alerting/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Initial Thoughts This new feature capability offered in the Teams Admin Center is a nice complementary option to monitor devices and alert Admins when they go offline.
A great use scenario is for Conference Room devices or Executive level phones and while it&rsquo;s not preventative, it does help Admins to react fast when devices go offline whether at a individual or site level.
Configuration Validate permissions to create a Team/Channel]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Microsoft Teams IP Phones Endpoint Manager Android Complaince Exclusion</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/2021-05-13-teams-ip-phones-endpoint-manager-android-compliance-exclusion/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>David Ponce de Leon</author>
    <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/posts/2021-05-13-teams-ip-phones-endpoint-manager-android-compliance-exclusion/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Issue Recently encountered an issue where IP Phones (Polycom CCX) were unable to register to Azure AD and would not appear in the Microsoft Teams Admin Center list of IP Phone devices. Most times this should not be an issue except if the company has Intune enabled and endpoint manager resctricting devices from registering due to compliance policies.
Solution I knew there were some recommendations to exclude these phones from any device compliance as it could create more harm than good and not gaining a full set of features for these devices since all software and firmware can be pushed through the teams admin center.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
